So, Enthropic is joining the Agentic
browsing race, but they're not building
a browser. Instead, they decided to
create a Chrome extension, which they're
calling Claude for Chrome, which I think
is a very smart move. Now, this is under
early research preview. Only a subset of
Max subscribers have access. I am one of
them. So in this video I'm going to show
you how the experience looks like. What
are some of the strengths and weaknesses
and also some example use cases with
real demos. Every AI company is trying
to build some sort of agentic browsing
experience. We have seen a comment from
Perplexity. There are rumors that OpenAI
is also working on an agentic browser.
Google already has Gemini and Chrome and
now Enthropic is joining the ranks. But
with the agentic browsing experience,
you also are going to see some new
prompt injection techniques and
vulnerabilities. So, we're going to look
at some of those later in the video. But
first, let me walk you through how does
it look like and then let me show you
some example use cases. Here's how the
experience looks like. It's a a Chrome
extension. When you click on it, you
going to see that this sidebar opens.
It's a chat interf inter interface very
similar to Gemini claude or chat GPT.
But let me walk you through a few demos.
So the first test was to ask the agent
to post something on my behalf to X. It
was first able to navigate to X without
any problems and then posted that
message. By default, it's going to ask
for your permission before taking any
actions. You can change this default
behavior by either allowing a subset of
actions or allowing the agent to take
any action if you're feeling
adventurous. The way it works is that
it's going to first take a screenshot of
the web page that it's looking at. Then
it plans the action that it's going to
perform. After performing an action, it
again takes a screenshot to confirm the
action has been taken and what results
have been achieved. In my case, it first
posted the message, but before hitting
the post button again, it asked for my
permission, which is a very interesting
design choice, especially if you're
looking at sensitive information. But if
you're logged into your account, say for
example on X or Gmail, then this can
really help you automate some of the
tasks. The post is already live on X.
Let me show you some other examples.
Okay, for this next task, I asked the
agent to look for an apartment in a
specific area with a given price range,
but I also added some ambiguous
information to see how it's going to
deal with that. For example, I asked it
to look for a place with a backyard.
Usually on website like Zillow, they
don't mention backyard, but rather
mentions places with outdoor spaces. So
first it navigated to the Zillow website
within that city range which was pretty
nice to see. Then it also navigated to
input the price range that I had asked
for. Now the way the system works is
that it takes an action then usually
waits for two to three seconds and I
think this ensures that after the click
the page has been reloaded properly. So
it's a little on the slower side. This
whole thing took about 10 minutes.
That filter reduced the search space.
After that it applied the house filter
because we are specifically looking for
houses. That again reduced the search
space even further. And then it decided
to apply the other two filters which one
the first one was in laundry units and
the other one was outdoor spaces. The
action that it takes is very humanike
especially if it's working in a websites
that it hasn't seen before. So just like
humans it makes assumptions click on
things. If it goes to the wrong places
then tracks back and take the actions
again. Ultimately it was able to find
only one house. You can see this place
is extremely expensive but it worked.
Another use case is to use this as a
research agent that's going to help you
extract information from different
websites. So in this case I asked it to
look at the recent price action of
Nvidia stock and tell me what caused it.
So it started looking at different
websites and starting gathering
information from those. Now this is
extremely helpful. You can do a Google
search but Google search will just give
you index information at a high level
but in this case it's going to each
website individually and gathering
information from these web pages. So,
it's a lot more natural and it can read
a lot of different content really fast,
which I think makes it extremely useful
for a task like this. And at the end, it
correctly identified the root cause of
what caused the price action in the
Nvidia stock, which is pretty good.
Another use case would be to use it as a
research assistant if you are shopping.
In this case, I asked it to look for a
specific camera, but I did not specify
which websites to look at. First, it
decided to do Google search, which gives
it a baseline of the pricing. Then, it
decided to look at the shopping tab on
Google. After that, it started looking
at the same product on multiple
different websites. These included
Amazon, Best Buy, B&H, eBay, which is
pretty cool to see. It navigates from
one website to another one and it's
looking at the same product. This seem
to be able to look at a single tab at
the moment, which means that it's going
to move from one website to another one.
But the good thing is that it has
memory. So whenever it gathers
information from a website, it can put
it in its memory and reuse it later. So
ultimately it was able to give me a
list. I wanted to see whether it's going
to hallucinate the links. So I
specifically asked for links and
surprisingly it was able to remember the
links. The links actually worked which
is pretty neat. So it can be really
useful tool for initial search. Another
use case is going to be to download data
from internet. So in this case I asked
it to download the W9 form from the IRS
website. Now this test not only looks at
its capability to find information on
websites but I also wanted to see how
it's going to deal with downloading
files from the internet. I was testing
this in auto mode where it can take the
actions without asking me for explicit
permissions. So first it was able to
navigate to the proper place to find
that W9 form which is really good and
then it was also able to open that form
but after that something interesting
happened. So when it comes to
downloading anything,
even though if it's in the auto mode, it
will still ask for explicit permission,
which is a very good design choice. You
just don't want to trust these agents to
download malicious data files from
internet. This was really good and I
think it's a very good implementation
given Enthropic is a safety focused
company. Now it opened the save box but
the final click is going to be user
click or user permission. So I had to
click on the save in order to save the
actual file.
Another important use case is going to
be to fill out web forms on websites.
This is where these agents can be
extremely helpful. So I provided some
dummy information to the agent to fill
out the W W W W W W W W W W W W W W W W
W W W W W W W W W W W W W W W W W W W W
W W W W W form that was open on the IRS
website. Now this is where I started
seeing some very interesting things. But
first, it's not going to fill out any
sensitive information. So in this case
it told me that it's cannot fill out the
social security number which [snorts]
again I think is a very good design
pattern especially you don't want to
trust these agents with your sensitive
personal information or financial
information.
So it started filling out the form with
some initial information but then it got
stuck in a loop where it was describing
the correct actions to take where to
fill out the information but it was
looking at the wrong pages. This might
be due to the complexity of the task but
at the end the agent told me that it had
completely filled out all the
information that I have requested. But
then I had to remind the agent that
that's not the case. In fact, I said, "I
don't see all the information on the
form. I can only see the name filled
out. Can you confirm that it's correct?"
It took a screenshot again and went
back, started looking at the form, and
realized that it hasn't filled out the
form. Right? So, it was stuck in this
loop. I don't know if it has to do with
the complexity of the form or the length
of the document. I haven't replicated
the same behavior on any other web forms
yet. So if you get access, make sure to
test it out. It will be an interesting
test. But at the end of this test,
Claude was not able to fill out the W9
form based on the information that I
provided.
When it comes to sensitive information,
whether it's personal or financial,
Claude is very conservative. So for
example, if you ask it to access your
bank account or financial details,
Claude will take you to the website, but
it's not going to take any actions on
your behalf. Now, this is important,
especially I do not trust any of these
agents when it comes to financial or
personal information. So it's good to
see that Enthropic is taking this
seriously. Some of these other
implementation are using agents in a
sandbox. Again, I will not trust
inputting my account information into a
remote sandbox. So, at least this is
running locally, but still you want to
be very careful. This is currently
available to a select group of about
thousand max plan users. You can join
the weight list if you want. And as I
said, it's in a research preview. So, as
you saw, some of the things work, some
of them don't work. But the most
important thing that I wanted to
highlight towards the end of the video
was some of the vulnerabilities and new
attack vectors that are going to come
into play when we start using these
agentic browsing experiences. And they
have done some studies on mitigating
some of those. For example, prompt
injection is going to be a huge issue,
especially you can just put something in
a website embedded and the agent
probably is going to read an image with
certain instructions, right? Or will
execute malicious code. So in order to
mitigate against those, first they have
site level permission. So user can grant
or revoke cloud's access to specific
websites at any time in the settings.
Actually, if you go to uh settings here,
you're going to see a list of websites
that you have approved. So, you can
remove those from permissions if you
want. And the second thing is action
confirmation. So, as we saw with every
action, cloud is going to ask you for
permission unless you enable skip
permissions. Even though if you skip
permissions in the autonomous mode,
cloud will still not do certain actions.
for example, it's not going to access
your private data or try to log into
your bank account or maybe input your
SSN. So, for example, they say that we
have blocked cloud from using websites
from certain high-risk categories such
as financial services, adult content,
and pirated content. And this is
critical because at this point, we can't
really trust these agentic systems or
their capabilities. So, this is a really
good mitigation. But still I think you
want to make sure that you observe the
actions the agent is taking. Now with
this these mitigations they show that
the current system with sonnet 4 which I
believe is the model driving the agent
they were able to reduce prompt
injection vulnerabilities to 11%. If you
don't include these mitigation it's
about 23%. So almost 50% reduction which
is great but still 11% is a lot. They
have done some specific red teamings for
specific attack vectors. So one of them
is hidden malicious form fields in web
pages where they're not visible to users
but cloud can read them. So on a
challenge set of four browser specific
attack types they say that they have
mitigated the error rate from almost 36%
to 0%. Which is great right? But that's
just one challenge, right? So therefore
they say that before we make cloud for
Chrome widely available, we want to
expand the universe of attacks, we are
thinking about and learn how to get
these percentages much closer to zero.
So with these new browsing experiences,
I think there going to be a lot to do
for security. Also do let me know what
you think about these agentic browsers
and how would these come into play in
your own workflows. Anyways, I hope you
found this video useful.